片名：《贝奥武甫》
Hrothgar! Hrothgar! Hrothgar!
洛斯戈! 洛斯戈! 洛斯戈!
I want mead !
把蜜酒拿来！
Give me some mead, my Queen !
王后，为我倒上蜜酒！
丹麦
公元507年
Thank you, my beautiful Queen.
谢谢，我美貌的王后
Hrothgar! Hrothgar! Hrothgar!
洛斯戈! 洛斯戈! 洛斯戈!
This is how it works, Aesher.
事情乃是这样，亚瑟
Aer you die,
you wouldn't really be dead
你在身后未必会化为尘埃
providing you have accepted him
as the one and only God.
只要你信他，尊他是唯一的神（指基督）
All right, back! Back!
好了，大伙回来
Here, my beauty, give me a kiss.
我的美人，吻我一个
I want a kiss! Give me a kiss!
I want a kiss!
我要你吻我一个，吻一个
Please, stop it!
不要这样！
More!
再来！
My thanes, my beautiful thanes!
诸位王民，我俊骁的王民！
One year ago, I, Hrothgar, your King
一年前，我，洛斯戈，你们的王
swore that we would
celebrate our victories
许下诺言，将把我们的功绩庆祝
in a new hall, mighty and beautiful !
在一个至高、壮美的宫殿
Have I not kept my oath? Yeah.
- 我可曾遵循誓言？
- 是的！
In this hall, we shall divide
the spoils of our conquests,
在这大殿，我们把掠获的战利品分发
the gold and the treasure.
有黄金，有财宝
And this shall be a place of merriment,
joy, and fornication !
让这座大殿充满欢乐，喜悦
肉体的欢愉！
From now until the end of time,
I name this hall Herot!
从此，我命此殿为西奥鹿特
直至时间尽头！
Treasure!
Let's hand out some treasure!
财宝！我们把财宝分发！
Give me some of that!
给我！
From my conquests!
攻城略地的奖赏！
Unferth !
安浮斯!
For Unferth, for Unferth,
my wisest advisor,
赏与安浮斯，赏与安浮斯
最智慧的策士
violator of virgins
and best and bravest of brave brawlers.
处女的掠夺者
最好，最勇猛的诡辩家！
Unferth, where the hell are you,
you weasel-faced bastard?
安浮斯，你在哪？
你这眼贼颊长的混账
I'm here, my King.
我在这，我的王
Unferth, come here, you ungrateful lout!
安浮斯，过来，你这忘恩负义的小丑
Hrothgar! Hrothgar! Hrothgar!
洛斯戈! 洛斯戈! 洛斯戈!
He faced a demon dragon
When other men would freeze
独面魔样巨龙，常人血冷脚痹
And then, my lords, he took his sword
And brought it to its knees. . .
吾王剑拔出鞘，巨龙膝折难立
Hrothgar! Hrothgar!
洛斯戈! 洛斯戈!
The greatest of our kings
吾王世间无敌
He broke the dragon's wings
力斩妖龙双翼
Hrothgar! Hrothgar!
洛斯戈! 洛斯戈!
The kingdom fell in darkness
And shadows ruled the night
王地阴霾入遁，黑影夜深频来
With no sign of dawn, he soldiered on
And brought us back to life
曙光指日无望，吾王力挽狂澜
Hrothgar! Hrothgar!
洛斯戈! 洛斯戈!
He never shook your faith
笃信吾王不移
Hrothgar! Hrothgar!
洛斯戈! 洛斯戈!
Let eve cup be raised
满斟万杯同举！
Hrothgar! Hrothgar!
洛斯戈! 洛斯戈!
He offered us protection
When monsters roamed the land
吾王庇佑众生，哪怕魔怪横行
And one by one, he took them on
They perished at his hand
张牙舞爪而来，接二连三送命
Mead !
蜜酒!
You're spilling it. Where's my mead?
You're spilling it.
你弄洒了蜜酒，蜜酒哪里去了？
你弄洒了
You're spilling it!
被你弄洒了！
Cain, you clumsy idiot!
该隐，你这拙笨的蠢夫！
How dare you waste the King's mead?
居然敢浪费吾王的蜜酒？
He rose up like a savior
When eve hope was gone
吾王鼎立救世，即便希望渺茫
The beast was gored
and peace restored
斩怪驱魔和平世
His memo will live on
英名永不忘
Hrothgar! Hrothgar!
洛斯戈! 洛斯戈!
Let eve cup be raised
满斟万杯同举！
Hrothgar! Hrothgar!
洛斯戈! 洛斯戈!
Now and forever
功名千秋万世！
A sword ! Give me a sword !
剑！给我一把剑！
Come! Arm yourselves!
快，拿起武器！
Stay down, my Lady!
王后，快蹲下！
-Give me a sword ! A sword !
-My Lord !
- 剑！给我一把剑！
- 殿下！
No!
不要！
Fight me!
跟我打！
Fight me.
跟我打
You fight me, damn you.
你来战我，混账
Nay.
不
What was that?
那是什么？
Grendel.
哥伦德
Grendel, what have you done?
哥伦德，你做了什么？
What a  done, Grendel?
你做了什么，哥伦德？
母亲
Fish and wolf and bear
鱼，狼，熊
and sheep or o,
或几只羊可以
ac nan men.
别碰人类
人
（听不懂）
Men, Grendel.
人，哥伦德
They have slain so many of our kind.
猎杀了我众多族类
（听不懂）
Was Hrothgar there?
洛斯戈也在吗？
我
没伤他
我没伤他 没，没
Good.
好
Good boy.
好孩子
And tender.
乖
Men, build another pyre!
来人，再堆起一座柴堆
There's dry wood behind the stables.
厩后还有枯木
Then burn the dead.
来把死者燃葬
And seal the hall !
Close the doors and the windows.
把大殿封禁！闭上门和窗
And by the King's order,
王颁下的命令
there should be no singing
or merrymaking of any kind.
从此不许有歌声与欢畅
This place reeks of death.
这里满是死尸的恶臭
The scops are singing
the shame of Herot
诗人正在传唱西奥鹿特的耻辱
as far south as the middle kingdom
and as far north as the ice-lands.
南至中土的王国（今德国）
北及冰封的土地（今挪威，瑞典）
I've let it be known that
I will give half the gold in my kingdom
我已承诺，将王国一半的黄金
to any man who can rid us of Grendel.
赏给为我们杀死哥伦德的人
My King, for deliverance
吾王，为求解救
our people sacrifice goats and sheep
to Odin and Heimdall.
族民给奥丁和海姆达尔
祭上了公山羊，公绵羊（两位北欧神）
With your permission,
您是否允许
shall we also pray
to the new Roman god, Christ Jesus?
向罗马的神，耶稣基督祭献？
Perhaps he can li our affliction.
也许他，可以将我们的痛苦祛除
No, Unferth, no.
不， 安浮斯， 不要
No, the gods will do nothing for us
that we will not do for ourselves.
如果我们自己不想办法
神明也帮不上我们
What we need is a hero.
我们需要，一位英雄
Hold your oars up!
推起船桨！
And heave!
用力划！
Can you see the coast?
Can you see the Danes' guide-fire?
能不能望到岸？
有没有丹麦人引航的篝火？
I see nothing but the wind and the rain !
我只看到风和雨
No fire, no stars by which to navigate.
没有火光，没有星斗作导航
We're lost! Given to the sea!
失去了方向！
性命交给了大海！
The sea's my mother!
这海是我母亲
She'll never take me back
to her murky womb.
她不会再将我收回她黑蒙蒙的子宫
My mother was a fishwife in Uppland.
我母亲是亚兰的渔妇
I was rather hoping to die in battle
as a warrior should !
我宁可战死在沙场上！
Heave!
划！
The men are worried
the storm has no end, Beowulf.
大伙担忧
这永不停息的风暴，贝奥武甫
It's no earthly storm,
that much is for sure.
可以确定，这并非人间的风暴
But this demon's tempest
will not hold us out
但这恶魔卷起的暴风雨
无法阻挡我们
if we really want in !
因为我们想要活！
Who wants to live?
谁想要活？
We do!
我们！
Then pull your oars! Let's see you do it!
那就拉起桨来，给这天看看！
For Beowulf!
为贝奥武甫！
For gold !
为黄金！
For glory!
为荣耀！
Heave! Heave!
划！划！
Beowulf.
贝奥武甫
Hold fast!
拽住！
No.
不
Who are you?
From your dress, you are warriors.
你是谁？看装束，你是一名战士
Speak! Why should I
not run you through right now?
说！为何现我现在不该一枪将你刺穿？
We are Geats.
我们是基斯人
（瑞典部族）
I am Beowulf, son of Ecgtheow.
我是埃戈西奥之子，贝奥武甫是我的名字
We come seeking your Prince Hrothgar
in friendship.
我们以朋友的身份来见你们的王洛斯戈
They say you have a monster here?
有人说你们这里出现怪兽？
They say your lands are cursed.
有人说你们的土地已经被诅咒
Is that what they say?
他们是这样说的？
Bards sing of Hrothgar's shame
诗人把洛斯戈的耻辱吟唱
from the frozen North
to the shores of Vinland.
从冰冻的北方到文兰的海岸（疑指芬兰）
There's no shame
to be accursed by demons!
这里从未有被恶魔诅咒的耻辱
I am Beowulf!
And I am here to kill your monster.
我是贝奥武甫，我来这里杀死你们的怪兽
I thought there were no more heroes
foolish enough
我以为不会再有愚蠢的英雄
to come around here
and die for our gold.
到这里来，为我们的黄金而死
If we die, it'll be for glory, not for gold.
如果我们死了，那是为荣耀，而不是黄金
My Lord?
吾王？
There are warriors outside. Geats.
吾王，外面来了许多战士，基斯的战士
But they are no beggars,
并非为谋生讨赏
and their leader Beowulf
is an imposing. . .
其领袖贝奥武甫雄武……
Beowulf? Ecgtheow's little boy?
贝奥武甫？埃戈西奥的小娃娃？
Beowulf. Where is he? Where?
贝奥武甫？他在哪？哪里？
There you are.
Beowulf, welcome, my boy.
你在这，贝奥武甫，欢迎你，孩子
Welcome. Yes. How's your father?
欢迎你，你的父亲如何？
Dead.
死了
Died in battle with sea-raiders
o winters back.
与海上来的袭击者战斗而死
两个冬季之前
Well, he was a brave man.
是的，他勇敢非凡
May I ask why you have come to us
from across the sea?
我想问你，为何渡海而来？
I've come to kill your monster.
我来这里把你们的怪兽杀死
And to taste that famous mead of yours.
将你们美名传扬的蜜酒品尝
There have been many brave men
who have come to taste my Lord's mead
曾有众多勇猛之士来品尝吾王的蜜酒
and many who have sworn
to rid his hall of our nightmare.
许多人发誓驱散缠绕大殿梦魇
But in the morning,
there was nothing le of any of them
但曙光微露之际，他们已不见踪影
but blood to be cleaned from the floor
只有洒满地板的血迹，等待擦干
and the benches, and the walls.
桌椅，墙上的血迹
I have drunk nothing, yet.
我尚未喝到蜜酒
But I will kill your monster.
但我将杀死你们的怪兽
He will kill the monster.
Did you hear that? Grendel will die.
他将杀死怪兽，听见了吗？
哥伦德时日不多了
-Grendel?
-Yeah, the monster is called Grendel.
- 哥伦德？
- 是的，怪兽叫做哥伦德
Then I will kill your Grendel.
那我将杀死你们的哥伦德
I, Beowulf,
killed a tribe of giants on the Orkneys,
我，贝奥武甫
曾在奥克尼杀光一个巨人的部族
crushed the skulls of sea-serpents,
曾在海中击碎海怪的脑骨
and this troll of yours
will trouble you no more.
这个怪兽将不再使你们困扰
A hero! A hero!
I knew the sea would bring us a hero!
英雄！英雄！
我知道大海会给我们送来英雄
So will you go up to the moors,
to the dark pool by the cave
那么，你是否将深入沼泽
走入洞穴中黑暗的污池
and kill the monster in its den?
在怪兽的巢穴将它杀死？
I have 1 4 brave thanes with me.
We have been long at sea.
我带来了十四位骁勇的战士
在海上沉浮已久
It is high time, mighty Hrothgar,
to break open your golden mead
现在正是时候，强大的洛斯戈
拿出你黄金般流淌的蜜酒
famed across the world
无人不知的佳酿
and to feast
in your legendary mead hall.
在你传说中的蜜殿里畅饮
The mead hall has been sealed
by his Lord's order.
蜜殿已经被吾王下令封禁
Merrymaking in the hall
brings the devil, Grendel.
大殿中的欢乐会带来魔鬼，那哥伦德
Well, then.
那就这样
Open the mead hall ! Let's drink!
打开蜜殿！我们喝！
We don't want any trouble
with the locals.
我们不要跟这里的人惹上麻烦
Hondshew, make me feel
you're pretending to listen to me.
悍朔，我觉得你在假装听我讲话
It's only been five days
since you waved your wife goodbye.
你与的妻子挥别，不过仅仅五天
Five days? In the name of Odin,
no wonder my loins are burning !
已过了五天？奥丁我神
难怪我腹下炙热难忍！
Beowulf, there you are.
贝奥武甫，你在这
I was thinking about your father.
Great man.
我正想着你的父亲，一位强人
He was fleeing the Wulfings
当年他从武甫人那里逃出
and he'd killed one of them
with his bare hands.
空手将他们的一个族人杀死
-Heatholaf.
-That's it, yeah. That's right.
- 西索拉夫
- 就是他，没错
I paid the blood debt for your father,
and he swore his oath to me.
我替你父亲偿还了血债（用财产）
于是他宣誓效忠于我
So I saved his skin,
and you're here to save ours, that right?
我救了他一命，所以你把我们拯救
是这样吧？
All hail the great Beowulf,
荣耀属于伟大的贝奥武甫
come to save
our pathetic Danish skins, eh?
来把我们丹麦人可怜的小命拯救，啊？
And we are so damned grateful,
mighty Beowulf.
我们至死感激不尽，强大的贝奥武甫
But can I ask a question,
as a huge admirer of yours?
但有一问题不知该不该问
秉着对你狂热的仰慕
There was another Beowulf
I heard tell of
我听说有另一位贝奥武甫
who challenged Brecca the Mighty to
a swimming race out on the open sea.
挑战无敌的布勒卡，在深海里赛泳
Was that you?
那人可是你？
I swam against Brecca.
我是和布勒卡赛泳
Because I thought
it had to be a different Beowulf,
我以为那定是另一位贝奥武甫
someone else of the same name.
另外一人，却有相同的名字
Because, you see,
the Beowulf I heard of
因为，我听说的这位贝奥武甫
swam against Brecca and lost.
与布勒卡赛泳，输了
He risked his life and Brecca's
此人用自己和布勒卡的生命做筹码
to serve his own vanity and pride.
来满足自己的虚荣和傲慢
A boastful fool.
一位自负的愚人
And he lost!
最后却输了
So I thought it had to be someone else.
所以，我想那定是他人
I swam against Brecca.
我是和布勒卡赛泳
But victory was his, not yours.
但胜利属于他，不属于你
A mighty warrior who cannot even
win a swimming match !
一位无敌的战士，却无法赢得赛泳
Speaking only for myself here,
且说我自己的想法
not only do I doubt that you will be
able to stand for a moment
我不仅质疑你能否有一个片刻
against Grendel,
抵挡住哥伦德
I doubt that you will even have the belly
to stay in the hall all night.
我质疑你是否有勇气在这大殿度过一夜
I find it difficult to argue with a drunk.
与醉人争辩是最难不过
But it's true, I did not win the race.
但你说的乃是事实，我没有赢得比赛
We swam for five days, neck and neck.
我们游过了五个昼夜，颈并着颈
l was conserving my strength
for the final stretch
我保藏着力量，为最后的冲刺
when this storm blew up
风暴突然地吹起
and with it came sea monsters.
带来了海中的怪兽
Again and again, the monsters attacked!
一次又一次，海怪接连袭来
Dark things from the sea's depths.
黑暗的事物，来自大海的深处
l hacked and l lashed
at these foul beasts with my sword,
我拿起宝剑
砍向这些污秽的怪兽，刺进他们的身体
spilling their guts into the sea.
它们剖开的肚肠，洒进大海
Beowulf!
贝奥武甫!
Then one of them seized me by its jaws
然后，其中一只把我咬住
and dragged me to the bottom.
拖我到了海底
l killed the monster with my own blade
被我用我的剑杀死
and I plunged it into its heart.
直插进心脏
Yes, of course. The sea monsters.
是的，海上的怪兽
And you killed, what was it? 20?
那么你杀了，有多少只？
二十只？
Nine.
九只
Last time it were three.
上次说的是三只
But would you do me the honor
of telling me your name?
那么，你能告知，你的姓名
I am Unferth, son of Ecglaf.
我是俄戈拉夫之子，安浮斯
Unferth, son of Ecglaf.
俄戈拉夫之子，安浮斯
I know who you are.
我知道你
They say you killed both your brothers
他们说你把你的两个兄弟杀死
when you witnessed them
having knowledge of your mother.
因为你撞见他们与你母亲私通
I have another true thing to tell you,
Unferth Kinslayer.
我还要告诉你另一个事实，弑亲的安浮斯
If your strength and heart
was as strong and fierce as your words,
假如你的勇气和你的心
如你的话语般强劲和锐利
Grendel would not feel free to murder
and gorge on your people
哥伦德便不能肆无忌惮地杀死你的族民
把他们吞食
without fear of retaliation.
绝不担心报复的索求
Tonight will be different!
这个夜晚将不一样
Tonight, he will find Geats waiting
for him, not frightened sheep
这个夜晚，他将发现等待他的基斯人
并非畏缩的羔羊
like you.
如你一样
Well done!
很好！
That's the spirit, Beowulf.
That's the spirit we need.
正是这种精神，贝奥武甫
我们正需要
So you will kill my Grendel for me,
will you?
那么，你将为我把哥伦德杀死，是吗？
Well, let's all drink in celebration
of the kill that is to come.
好的，我们来畅饮，把将要来的击杀庆祝
Lips ripe as the berries in June
唇瓣，六月梅熟
Red the rose, red the rose
玫瑰，红，玫瑰，红
Skin pale as the light of the moon
肤淡，云清月素
Gently as she goes
轻轻，她的脚步
Eyes blue as the sea and the sky
蓝眸，海天之合
Beowulf. Come.
贝奥武甫，来！
Water flows, water flows
溪水，流，溪水，流
Come with me.
I want to show you something.
过来，我要给你看一样东西
Heart burning like fire in the night
心儿，静静夜火
Gently as she goes
轻轻，她的脚步
Come.
来
There.
看
The Royal Dragon Horn.
王者的龙角
It is beautiful.
很美
Isn't it magnificent?
美极了吧？
She's the prize of my treasure.
她是我瑰宝中的珍宝
I claimed her aer my battle with Fafnir,
the dragon of the Northern moors.
在战胜了盘踞在北方沼泽的龙，法夫那之后
我把她得到
Nearly cost me my life.
几乎把性命赔上
And there's a so spot
under the throat, there.
在颈下有一处弱点，这里
See? You have to go in
with a knife or a dagger.
看到吗？要用刀或匕首直插进去
It's the only way you can kill a dragon.
龙只有这样才能被杀死
I wonder how many men
have died for love of her beauty.
不知道曾有多少勇士
为获得这美人的心而逝去
Can you blame them?
也怪不得他们
If you destroy my Grendel for me,
如果你为我把哥伦德杀死
she'll be yours forever
and ever and ever.
她将属于你，永远，永远
You do me great honor.
您赐予了我极大的荣耀
It is we who are honored.
是我们的荣耀
Is that your demon?
这可是你们的恶魔？
That was a wolf.
You don't hear Grendel when he comes.
那不过是狼
没有任何声音预示哥伦德的到来
No? Well, you'll hear me, I promise.
没有？那可好，我“到”时会让你听到
Come on, my mighty lust limb
can transport you to paradise,
来吧，我强大的爱的枝干
会将你送向天国
to ecstasy and back.
到狂醉而止
No other man
will ever be able to satis you again.
再不会有人让你如此满足
-Sorry.
-Come on !
- 抱歉
- 来嘛
-I said no and I meant no.
-Why not?
- 我说不，是认真的
- 为什么？
Because it's late and it's dark and the
monster could arrive at any moment!
因为天色已晚，黑夜降临
怪兽随时可能出现
Well, then, how about a quick gobble?
好吧，那么快快来个鸡啄米如何？
The hour is upon us.
时刻到了
This old man needs his sleep.
老人需要他的睡眠
Where's my beautiful bedmate?
Come, my love.
我美貌的寝伴在哪？
来，我的爱
In a moment.
一会儿
Come, Wealthow,
let us pound the pillows.
我们来拿枕头戏耍
Don't touch me!
别碰我！
That's the spirit, my girl.
要的正是这种精神，我的女孩
My Lord !
吾王！
Perhaps Her Majesty
could grace our ears
王后可以为我们的耳朵赐福
with one more melody
before we all retire?
在我们就寝之前，用一段美妙的乐曲
It's the least I can do.
这便是我可以做的
Beowulf, I'll hope to see you
in the morning, Odin willing.
贝奥武甫，希望在曙光微露时见你
从奥丁的愿
And make sure
your thanes secure the doors.
记得让你的战士把屋门关紧
Good night. Good night.
晚安，晚安
Good night, Beowulf.
Watch out for sea monsters.
晚安，贝奥武甫，留神海中的怪兽
I'm sure your imagination
must be teeming with them.
它们定将在你的想像中聚集
Just wait
耐心等待
Though wide he may roam
虽然天涯徜徉
Always a hero comes home
英雄，终会还乡
He goes where no one has gone
走遍无人之境
But always a hero comes home
英雄，终会还乡
He goes where no one has gone
走遍无人之境
But always a hero comes home
英雄，终会还乡
That was beautiful.
真美
You need to go now, Your Majesty.
您该走了，王后殿下
Of course. Grendel.
是的，哥伦德
The demon is my husband's shame.
那恶魔是我丈夫的耻辱
It's not a shame, it's a curse.
不是耻辱，乃是诅咒
No, shame.
不，耻辱
My husband has no other. No sons.
我的丈夫无人可以依靠
没有子嗣
And he will have no more,
for all his talk.
他也不愿有，依他所说
Oy, Hondshew. How was she?
噢，悍朔，她怎么样？
Nah. Not my type.
不，不是我喜欢的
I know your type.
我知道你喜欢什么
Lord Beowulf, what are you doing?
贝奥武甫大人，你要做什么？
The creature has no sword, no armor.
这怪物没有剑持，没有盔甲护体
And I have no weapon
capable of slaying a monster.
我也没有可伤它的兵器
We shall fight as equals.
我们将公平地斗
And fate
命运
shall decide.
将做出裁决
Good. Tie it off with more chain.
好，多用些铁链捆锁
Enough frican' about!
不要再打闹！
You're mad, you know that?
你太疯狂了，知道吗？
Yes.
知道
Something vexes you, my Wiglaf?
什么事困扰着你，维格拉夫
I don't like the smell of this one,
my Lord.
我有不好的预感，大人
The men are unprepared.
战士们毫无防备
They're distracted.
心思涣散
Too many untended women here!
这里渴望爱的女人太多！
Abstinence prior to battle is essential !
战前必须节欲！
A warrior's mind must be unblurred,
my Lord.
战士必须心无旁骛，大人
Good night, Wiglaf.
晚安，维格拉夫
And while you're sleeping,
what're we meant to do?
你睡时我们要做什么？
Sing ! Loudly!
唱！放声唱！
Well, you heard him.
He wants us to sing. So sing !
好，都听见了，要我们唱歌
唱！
Olaf, sing !
奥拉夫，唱！
There was a dozen virgins
处女一十二个
Friesians, Danes and Franks
弗里西，丹麦，法朗人
We took them for some swifan
And all we got were wanks
本想快乐成双，结果渎自身伤
Oh, we are Beowulf's army
Each a mighty thane
噢！贝奥武甫军壮
个个万夫难当
We'll pummel your asses
And ravage your lasses
踢你屁股，玩你婆娘
Then do it all over again
一遍又一遍
The fattest of the virgins
l knew her for a whore
处女中她最圆，婆娘数她最贱
l gave her all my codpiece
And still she wanted more
用尽浑身解数，还要重来一遍
Her sister was from Noay
She cost me 20 groats
妹妹来自挪威，换我二十银币
She showed me there was more ways
Than one to sow my oats
花样技巧百出，飘然上天入地
Her mother was from lceland
And she was mighty hot
妈妈来自冰岛，熊熊烈火燃烧
She'd need a whole damn iceberg
To cool her burning. . .
非得冰山出马，冷却……
Grendel. He knocks.
哥伦德，敲门
That must be my sweet plum, Yrsa.
定是我的甜李子，厄萨
She's ready for me
to taste her juicy fruit.
要把她的汁果与我品尝
My Lord.
- 大人
- 要把她的汁果与我品尝
Patience, patience, my love.
莫急，莫急，我的爱
No! Hondshew! No!
不！悍朔！别动
Swife me! It's the frican' monster!
天啊，就是这鬼怪兽
I swear, the bastard has no pintel !
我证明，这浑货没有阴茎！
-No pintel.
-.
- 没阴茎
- 是
-The demon shrinks!
-It shrinks! It shrinks!
- 恶魔缩小了！
- 它缩小了！
Demon !
恶魔！
Your bloodletting
days are finished, demon !
你杀戮的日子结束了，恶魔！
你…是…地狱的…魔？
It speaks. It speaks!
它说话了！说话了！
你…是…谁？
I am ripper, tearer, slasher, gouger.
我是，撕肝的钩，扯肺的镰
断肠的刃，剜心的尖
I am the teeth in the darkness,
the talons in the night.
黑暗的尖齿，深夜的魔爪
Mine is strength and lust and power!
我的名字是力量，欲火，和强权！
I am Beowulf!
我是，贝奥武甫!
Grendel's arm !
哥伦德的手臂！
You've done it!
你成功了！
He's done it!
他成功了！
He's torn the limbs from the beast!
Beowulf has killed him !
他扯下了恶魔的手臂！
贝奥武甫打死了恶魔！
-Hail, Beowulf!
- 万岁，贝奥武甫!
My Lord, Beowulf has killed the demon !
陛下，贝奥武甫杀死了恶魔
Odin be praised.
赞美奥丁
-Go tell the scops. Spread the word !
-Yes, my Lord.
- 下命让诗人将此事传颂！
- 是，陛下
Tomorrow will be
a glorious day of rejoicing.
明天是欢欣荣耀的日子
Our nightmare is over.
梦魇已经散去
Come to bed, my sweet.
上床来吧，我的爱
My kingdom needs an heir!
I need a son ! It's time you did your duty.
王国需要未来的国王！
我要子嗣！此时你该把义务行使！
How can I ever lay with you,
knowing you laid with her?
我已知你和她睡躺，如何再与你共床？
I should never have told you.
我不该告诉你
不该告诉你
哥伦德，吾子
My poor son.
我可怜的孩子
母亲
我受伤了，母亲
Sleep now, my son.
睡吧，我的孩子
他伤我，母亲
Who murdered you, my son?
是谁伤你，我的孩子？
他把我的手臂撕下
He will pay, een darling.
他会补偿的，我的心肝
这人是谁？
他是最强壮的
最强壮的
他是人？
是
那人是
贝奥武甫
Beowulf.
They were great warriors.
他们曾是强大的战士
They died a foul death.
但死于邪恶
They were murdered by a foul creature
from the depths of hell.
被生于地狱深处的秽物杀害
The bards
will sing of their glory forever.
他们的光荣将被一代代诗人传颂
Come, let us drink to their memory.
来，我们来饮酒，将他们纪念
I want you to raise the first cup.
我希望你第一个举起酒杯
I am not in the mood for merrymaking.
我没有心思寻乐
I'll ride down to the mooring,
prepare the boat.
我要去停泊之地，把船备好
We still leave tomorrow, on the tide,
do we not?
明天潮起时，我们便离开，是不是这样？
.
是的
My thanes, my friends, brothers,
我的王民，我的朋友，我的亲人
this place for me
has been a hall of sadness.
这个大殿曾是我伤心的地方
And for all of us,
是你们
it has been a place of misery,
bloodshed, and death.
感受痛苦，流血，死亡的地方
But today,
the monster's reign has ended.
今天，怪兽的统治结束了
They say he ripped the monster's
limb off with his bare hands.
听说他撕下了那怪兽的胳膊，仅凭一双手
I wonder if Beowulf's strength is only
in his arms, or in his legs as well,
不知贝奥武甫的力量是只在双臂
还是同样充满了下肢
all three of them?
那三条腿
Well, aer the feast tonight,
I'm sure you can find out, Gitte.
今天晚宴结束以后，你便可知道，吉塔
Me? It's not me he wants, my Queen.
我吗？他想的可不是我，王后
Bring it here!
拿上来！
Wealthow, my love,
薇娥修，我的爱
why don't you do the honors?
不如你来把这荣耀传递
For you, my Lord.
属于你，大人
Thank you, great King.
感谢，英明的王
And all of you,
谢谢大家
I wish you'd have been there last night
to see me kill the monster.
希望你们曾亲眼看到昨夜我把怪物杀死
I was asleep when he arrived.
他来时，我正在睡梦中
He ripped open the doors
with his bare hands.
大门被他的双手砸破
He stood 20 feet tall,
possessing the strength of 1 0 men.
他立起二十余尺，力量足抵十人
（原诗中贝奥武甫单手抵三十人）
I looked at him and said,
"I am Beowulf!"
我盯着他，说，我是贝奥武甫
Brave thane.
勇猛的战士
My Queen.
王后
I love you.
我爱你
I want you, my King.
我想属于你，我的王
Only you.
只想属于你
meen looviyend.
我的英雄，我的爱
I don't understand.
我不懂
Where's your husband?
你的丈夫呢？
Dead.
死了
Dead?
死了？
This is a dream.
这一定是梦
This is not happening.
You're just a dream.
这不可能，你只是梦
Me, darling? A dream?
我，亲爱的，是梦？
Give me a child.
Enter me and give me a son !
给我孩子，进入我，给我一个儿子！
In the name of Odin !
奥丁神啊！
Is Grendel not dead?
难道哥伦德复活？
Has he grown his arm anew?
断臂重新长出？
It's not Grendel.
不是哥伦德
Not Grendel? Then who?
不是哥伦德？那是谁？
His mother.
他的母亲
It's Grendel you killed.
因为你杀了哥伦德
I had hoped his mother
had le the land long, long ago.
我本希望他的母亲早已离开这片土地
How many monsters must I slay?
我到底要杀几只怪兽？
Grendel's mother? Father?
Grendel's uncle?
哥伦德的母亲？父亲？叔叔？
Must I hack down
a whole family tree of demons?
要我把恶魔一家子连根拔起？
She is the last of them.
她是最后一个
With her gone,
她去了以后
demonkind will slip back
into the darkness from whence it came.
恶魔一族将退回到他们出生的黑暗中去
Where it belongs.
命定的地方
And the mother's mate?
Where is Grendel's father?
他妈妈的伴侣在哪？他的父亲
Grendel's father
can do no harm to man.
哥伦德的父亲不会害人
Beowulf,
贝奥武甫
I was wrong to doubt you before,
and I shall not again.
之前对你质疑，是我的错，不会再犯
Yours is the blood of courage.
I beg your forgiveness.
你的鲜血中流淌着勇气
我请求你的原谅
Granted.
我原谅
Cain ! Cain !
该隐！该隐！
Take my sword.
It belonged to my father's father.
带上我的宝剑，他曾属于我父亲的父亲
It's called "Hrunting."
赫伦汀是它的名字
That sword is no match
for demon magic.
这把剑无法与恶魔的魔法抗衡
I'm sorry I ever doubted you.
我抱歉曾经质疑你
No, I'm sorry I mentioned
you murdered your brothers.
不，我抱歉提起你弑兄的往事
They were hasty words.
那是一时冲动的言辞
Unferth, I may not return.
安浮斯，我可能无法回返
Your ancestral sword
might be lost with me.
你祖先留下的宝剑也会随我而去
As long as it is with you,
it will never be lost.
只要他随着你，便永远不会逝去
And you, mighty Wiglaf,
强大的维格拉夫，你呢
are you still with me?
是否还与我一起
To the end.
至死为止
Look.
看
She's probably a water demon.
她可能是水中的魔怪
You don't want to meet her
in her element.
你不要与她在水中对抗
I know.
我知道
Do you want me to go in with you?
要我跟你一起吗？
Good.
好
I'll be here.
我等在这
I see you've brought me treasure.
你好像为我带来了宝物
Show yourself!
现出身来！
What are you?
你是什么东西？
Are you the one they call Beowulf?
你是所说的贝奥武甫吗？
The Bee-Wolf.
吃蜜蜂的狼
The bear.
那熊
Such a strong man you are.
你真的十分强壮
With the strength of a king.
拥有着王者的力量
The king you will one day become.
有一天，你会成王
What do you know of me, demon?
你了解我什么，恶魔？
I know that underneath your glamour
我知道你的魅惑力下隐藏着
you're as much a monster
as my son, Grendel.
邪恶，与我的儿子哥伦德一样
My glamour?
我的魅惑力？
One needs glamour to become a king.
人若要成王需要魅惑力
A man like you could own
the greatest tale ever sung.
人如你这样可以成为最伟大的史诗的主角
Your story would live on
你的故事将流传下去
when everything now alive is dust.
即便今日生的已落为尘埃
Beowulf.
贝奥武甫
It has been a long time
已经过了很久
since a man has come to visit me.
自从有人来到这里，与我相会
I need no sword to kill you.
我无需用剑便可杀你
Of course you don't, my love.
你当然不需用，我的爱
You took a son from me.
你带走了我的儿子
Give me a son, brave thane.
给我一个儿子，勇猛的战士
Stay with me.
留下来
Love me.
爱我
Love me
and I shall weave you riches
beyond imagination.
我会让你富有世人难以想象的资财
I shall make you
我会让你成为
the greatest king that ever lived.
永世间最伟大的王
As long as you hold me in your heart
只要你在你的心里把我保存
and this golden horn
remains in my keeping,
并这把黄金角留给我
you will forever be king.
你便会永生为王
Forever strong,
永远雄健
mighty
强大
and all powerful.
无所不能
This I promise.
我向你许诺
This I swear.
对你发誓
My Lord.
陛下
It's dead, my Lady.
已经死的，王后陛下
When I finished off
Grendel's monstrous mother,
我杀死了哥伦德母亲之后
I severed the brute's head.
砍下了这畜生的头
Our curse is lied.
我们的诅咒解除了
Our curse is lied. Odin be praised !
我们的诅咒解除了，赞美奥丁
Beowulf be praised !
赞美贝奥武甫！
Our curse is lied.
我们的诅咒解除了
Take this out of my sight. Unferth !
把这个从我面前拿开，安浮斯
Into the sea, quickly.
扔进大海，快
I plunged Hrunting
into Grendel's mother's chest
我把赫伦汀刺进了哥伦德母亲的胸膛
and when I pulled the sword
free from her corpse,
待我把剑从尸体中拔出
the creature sprang back to life,
这怪物便又活过来
so I plunged the sword back into
the hag's chest and there it will stay.
于是我再次把剑插入这女妖的胸膛
剑留在了那里
Till Ragnarok, huh?
直到世界末日
And our people shall be grateful
till the Ragnarok.
我们的族民也会永远感激你
直到世界末日
More mead, my Lord?
是否还要蜜酒，大人
.
是
And the drinking horn, do you have it?
那饮酒的黄金角，可在身边？
No.
不
I knew the greedy witch desired it,
so I threw it into the swamp.
我料想那女妖贪婪，便把黄金角扔进沼泽
And when she followed,
that's where I struck,
她追随而去，才被我趁机刺中
with the mighty sword Hrunting.
用那把强大的赫伦汀剑
When she was dead, I looked for it,
but it was gone forever.
杀死她后，我曾找寻过
但那黄金角已消失不见
Then find our hero another cup,
my love.
那么为我们的英雄另取一个杯，我的爱
First, the hero and I must talk.
首先，英雄和我要有一番会谈
Beowulf.
贝奥武甫
So you brought back
the head of Grendel.
你带回了哥伦德的头
What about the head of the mother?
他母亲的头在哪里？
With her dead and cold in the bog,
她已冰冷无生气地躺在池沼中
is it not enough
to return one monster's head?
难道一个怪物的头还不够？
Did you kill her?
你是否杀死了她
Would you like to hear the story of my
struggle against this monstrous hag?
你想听我再次讲述与那凶暴妖女的搏斗？
She's no hag, Beowulf.
We both know that.
她不是妖女，贝奥武甫
你我二人心里明白
But answer me, did you kill her?
不过你要回答，你是否杀死了她
Would I have been able to escape her,
had I not?
我如何能够逃脱，如果我没有杀死她
Grendel is dead.
That's all that matters to me.
哥伦德死了，我只关心这
He can bother me no more.
他不会再把我骚扰
The mother, "the hag,"
she's not my curse.
那母亲，“妖女”，并不是我的诅咒
Not anymore.
不再是了
Listen to me!
听我说！
Because my Lord Beowulf
is a mighty hero
因为贝奥武甫大人是无比的英雄
and because
he killed the demon Grendel
杀死了哥伦德恶魔
and laid its mother in her grave. . .
并将它的母亲放躺在坟墓之中……
（放躺有性事之意）
-To Beowulf!
-Long live Beowulf!
- 敬贝奥武甫！
- 贝奥武甫永生！
. . .and because I have no heir,
……而且，我没有后代
I have no sons,
没有子嗣
I declare that on my death,
所以，我宣明，在我死后
all that I possess, my kingdom,
我的一切，我的王国
my hall of sadness and shame,
我的哀伤和耻辱的大殿
and even my lovely young Queen,
甚至我年轻貌美的王后
my Wealthow,
我的薇娥修
everything, everything
所有，所有
I leave to this, our hero.
都将留给，我们的英雄
-But, my Lord. . .
-I have spoken !
- 但是，吾王……
- 我已说明！
I have spoken !
我已说明！
When I am gone,
我故去之后
Beowulf, son of Ecgtheow,
shall be king !
埃戈西奥之子贝奥武甫将为王
Beowulf!
贝奥武甫
My Lord.
吾王
Everything in its time, Beowulf.
时候还未到，贝奥武甫
Hrothgar!
洛斯戈
He must have fallen.
他一定是跌下去了
-All hail King Beowulf.
- 贝奥武甫王万岁！
All hail King Beowulf.
贝奥武甫王万岁！
King Beowulf.
贝奥武甫王
Archers.
弓箭手
Archers!
弓箭手！
This is not battle, Wiglaf.
这不是战争，维格拉夫
This is slaughter.
这是屠杀
The Frisians want to make
themselves heroes, my Lord.
弗里兰人想当英雄，吾王
They want the bards
to sing of their deeds.
想被诗人传唱
It's going to be a short song.
如果会也是很短的一段
Now, can you blame them?
怎么能怪他们呢
Your legend is known
from the high seas
你的传说遍扬，从大陆之间的海面
and the snow barriers
to the great island kingdom.
冰雪的屏障，到强大的岛国（英国）
You are the monster slayer.
你是怪物的杀戮者
We men are the monsters now.
我们已经成了怪兽
The time of heroes is dead, Wiglaf.
英雄的时代消亡了，维格拉夫
The Christ God has killed it,
基督神已将她杀死
leaving humankind with nothing
but weeping martyrs,
给人类留下了一片虚无
只剩下哭泣的殉道士
fear and shame.
恐惧，和耻辱
Show me to Beowulf!
Show me to King Beowulf!
带我去见贝奥武甫，让我见贝奥武甫王！
Come on, Frisian. Speak up!
快，弗里兰人，说出来
Leave him !
放开他！
You think it sport
to mock your opponents in this fashion?
你们这样侮辱对手难道有趣？
Let him die quickly,
with some honor still intact.
让他痛快地死，趁他仍有荣誉留存
Coward !
懦夫！
Kill me yourself!
你来亲手杀我！
Balls! The king
must never engage in direct battle.
一派胡言，王不可亲自战斗
Kill the invader now! Do it quickly!
Put his head on a spear.
杀死这入侵者，立刻！
把他的头用枪挑起
Stop!
住手！
My Lord, the king
must not engage in direct battle.
吾王，王不可亲自战斗
Let him up.
让他起来
You want your name
in the Song of Beowulf?
你想在贝奥武甫之歌中刻上你的名字？
You think it should end with me killed
by some Frisian raider with no name?
你以为我的性命会在一个没有名字的
弗里兰入侵者手中葬送？
I'm Finn of Frisia
我是弗里西亚的斐恩
and my name
shall be remembered forever.
我的名字将被永远铭记
Only if you kill me!
除非你杀死我！
Otheise, you're nothing.
否则，你还是无名之辈
You think you're the first to try to kill me,
or the hundredth?
你以为你是第一个，或是第一百个
想把我杀死的人吗？
Well, let me tell you something, Frisian.
我来告诉你一件事，弗里兰人
The gods will not allow my death
by your feeble blade.
诸神不会让我的死亡，造于你无力的刀刃
The gods will not allow me to die
by a sword, or be taken by the sea.
诸神不会让我死于剑下，或沉于深海
The gods will not let me
pass in my sleep, ripe with age!
诸神不会让我在安眠中睡去
或岁月中熟落
Plant your ax here, Finn of Frisia.
Take my life.
你的斧子向这里砍，弗里西亚的斐恩
取走我的性命
Someone give him a sword, or I'll. . .
谁给他一把剑，否则我……
You'll what? Kill me?
你要如何？杀死我？
Well, kill me! Do it! Kill me! Kill me!
杀死我！动手！杀死我！杀死我！
You know why you can't kill me,
my friend?
知道为什么你不能杀死我，朋友？
'Cause I died many, many years ago
when I was young.
因为，在很多年以前，我还年轻时
我已经死了
Give him a gold piece
and send him home.
给他一块金币，送他回去
He has a story to tell.
他有故事可以讲述
Your Majesty?
陛下？
Are you hurt?
您伤到没有？
Not a scratch.
一丝也没有
So beautiful.
多么美丽
And so young.
年青
You know, Ursula, when I was young,
知道吗，俄苏拉，在我年青时
I used to think being a king
was about battling every morning
我曾以为当王便是每个日出作战
and counting the gold
and loot in the aernoon
每个日落清点黄金和战利品
and swiving beautiful women
every evening.
每个深夜与美丽的女人缠绵
But now, well, nothing is as good
as it should have been.
但是现在，一切都未如所想的那样美好
Not even the "swiving a beautiful woman
every night" part, Your Majesty?
包括“每夜与美丽的女人缠绵”，陛下？
Well, some nights, Ursula, some nights.
有些晚上，俄苏拉，有些晚上
Perhaps tonight?
也许今晚？
No, tonight, I feel my age upon me.
不，今晚，我感到年纪使我不便
Tomorrow, aer the celebrations.
明日，在庆典之后
We can't forget what tomorrow is,
can we now?
我们不会忘记明天是什么日子，是吧
Your day.
When the Song of Beowulf is told
属于你的，吟唱贝奥武甫之歌的日子
of how you lied the darkness
from the land.
讲述你如何将这片土地的黑暗驱散
And the day aer,
we celebrate the birth of Hallend Christ.
明日之后
还要庆祝终结宫殿的救世主的降生
I see you've survived.
我看见你活着回来了
Alas, my Queen,
啊，王后
the Frisian invaders
have been pushed into the sea.
弗里兰的入侵者已被赶回到海上
You are not a widow,
你还不是遗孀
yet.
目前
How comforting, my husband.
多么让我欣慰，丈夫
Hail, Beowulf! Hail, Beowulf!
万岁，贝奥武甫！万岁，贝奥武甫！
Unferth.
安浮斯
You're not celebrating
your King's glory tonight?
今晚你来庆祝吾王的荣耀？
I have something for the King.
我有东西呈献吾王
What is it?
什么东西？
I said I have something for the King.
我说我有东西呈献吾王
-Show it to me.
-I will not.
- 让我看看
- 我不让
You will show it to me first.
你要先给我过目
Bollocks, Wiglaf.
放屁，维格拉夫
I'll show it first to Beowulf.
The King needs to see it.
我要先让贝奥武甫过目
王想要看到它
The King
王
needs to see what?
想要看什么？
Lost and now found.
失去的，被找到了
A gi fit for a king.
与王相称的礼物
Do you recognize it?
你是否还记得？
Where did you find this?
你在哪里找到的？
On the moors. My slave Cain found it
on the barren hill where nothing grows.
我的奴隶该隐在沼泽里发现它
那寸草不生、瘠薄的山上
I beat him for treading near
such an unholy place.
我打他，怪他踏进不洁的地界
My Lord,
吾王
isn't this. . .
这难道不……
So, Lord Beowulf,
贝奥武甫王
it's come back to you,
aer all these years.
它回到了你的身边，经过这么多年以后
My Lord, this is the slave who found it.
吾王，便是这奴隶寻到它
Please, please don't kill me!
不，不要杀我！
Where did you find this treasure?
你在哪里找到这珍宝？
I'm sorry I ran away, Master.
But please don't hurt me no more.
逃走是我的错，主人
请不要再也伤害我
-Answer your King !
-Stop!
- 回答你的王！
- 住手！
Stop.
住手
Where?
哪里？
Up, up on the moors.
在沼泽之上
But I was gonna bring it back, Master.
I swear.
但我正要把它送回，主人
我发誓
Is that all?
这样而已？
No demon? No witch?
没有恶魔？女巫？
No woman?
没有女人？
Hail, Beowulf! Hail, Beowulf!
万岁，贝奥武甫! 万岁，贝奥武甫!
Hail, Beowulf!
Hail, Beowulf! Hail, Beowulf!
万岁，贝奥武甫! 万岁，贝奥武甫!
Look at you. You're nothing,
看看你，什么都不是
an empty nothing.
空空的，什么都不是
Come forth !
出来！
Show yourself!
现身！
Even with all your riches,
即便你拥有无数财宝
your kingdom, your power, your glory
王国，权利，荣誉
and your women.
和女人
Which one do you think
I should kill first,
我应该，先杀死哪一个？
your pretty little bedwarmer,
你那年轻漂亮的捂床睡伴
or your wise Queen?
还是你富有智慧的王后？
What are you?
你是什么？
I'm something you le behind,
我是你留下的东西
Father!
父亲！
Another restless night?
又一个不眠之夜？
It's all right, girl.
没关系，孩子
I'm not going to eat you.
我不会吃了你
He has bad dreams.
他做噩梦了
They've been coming more oen.
近来噩梦越来越频繁
He's a king, and kings
have a lot on their conscience.
他是王，王的心里总存有很多事
He calls your name in his sleep.
他在梦中喊起你的名字
Does he?
是吗？
I believe he still holds you in his heart.
我相信，他依然在心中把你保存
Do you?
真的吗？
I oen wonder
我经常在想
what happened.
为什么？
To us?
我们？
Too many secrets.
说不尽的秘密
God, help us.
神啊，救我们
What? What do you want of me?
什么……你想要我做什么？
I have a message for my father.
我要你把消息带给我的父亲
Tell me! What did this?
说！是什么东西？
I saw our whole village burn.
Children screaming as they died !
我看见整个村庄在燃烧
听到孩童死亡时的尖叫
I saw it, Your Majesty,
vomiting fire and smoke!
我看见它，陛下，吞吐着火与烟
Damn you ! What was it?
可憎的！那到底是什么？
A dragon !
龙！
-It's Unferth, my Lord !
-Unferth.
- 是安浮斯，陛下
- 安浮斯
You say a dragon did this? Stop!
你说这是龙的作为？停下！
You had an agreement.
你曾定下协议
You would not be harmed.
保证你，不受到伤害
But now the golden horn
has returned to you.
但现在黄金角已经归还于你
The agreement is ended.
那协议便已失效
Who? Who said that?
谁？谁说的！
"The sins of the fathers!"
“父辈的罪孽”
That's the last thing I heard.
这是我听见的最后的话语
The last thing before
my family was burned alive!
在我的全家被活活焚烧之前！
The sins of the fathers!
“父辈的罪孽”
Sins of the fathers!
The sins of the fathers!
“父辈的罪孽”
Take up your positions along
the northern edge of the great gorge.
在险峻的峡谷，北面的山崖上列队
It is our only hope if I fail.
那是我们仅存的希望，如果我失败
My Lord.
遵命，陛下
Don't go, I beg you !
不要去，我求你！
You are free. I release you.
你自由了，我将你释放
Find a good man and bear him children.
But bear him a son.
找一个出色的男人，怀上他的子嗣
带给他一个男孩
I don't want anyone else. I want you.
我不想要别人，我想要你
I am not the man you think me to be!
我不是你想像中的那样
You're a great man ! And a hero!
This I know to be true.
你是伟大的人，英雄！
我对这确信无疑
Then you are as foolish
as the rest of them !
那么你便和他们一样蒙昧无知
Very impressive, dear.
很漂亮，亲爱的人
But the armor suited you better
when you were younger.
但这盔甲更合你的身，当你年轻的时候
I'm sure it did.
当然如此
Why don't you take that poor girl
你为什么不收那可怜的姑娘
and live out your remaining years
in peace?
在安详中把余年度完
Let some young hero save us.
让某位年青的英雄，拯救我们
What?
什么？
And let the nightmare
start all over again?
让那梦魇再次浮现？
No. I visited this horror
upon my kingdom.
不，是我将这恐怖带到国土之上
-I must be the one to finish her.
-Her.
- 必须由我，来把她了结
- 她
Was she so beautiful, Beowulf?
她真的有那么美？贝奥武甫
A beauty so costly?
值得如此的代价？
Beautiful, and full of fine promises.
美丽，和无数美妙的誓言
I was weak.
我那时不坚定
I am sorry.
抱歉
So, so sorry.
十分的抱歉
I have always loved you, my Queen.
我一直爱你，我的王后
And I you.
我同你一样
Keep a memory of me,
在心中把我记住
not as a king or a hero,
不要记那王，或那英雄
but as a man,
记住我这个男人
fallible and flawed.
会犯错，不完美的
This is the place.
就是这个地方
Where you slayed Grendel's mother.
在这里，你曾将哥伦德的母亲斩杀
Wiglaf, I have no sons,
维格拉夫，我没有子嗣
and if this demon kills me,
I have arranged with the heralds
如果这恶魔将我杀死
我已传命于使者
that you shall be king.
你将为王
Don't speak of such things, my Lord.
不要说这样的话，陛下
Great friend,
there is something you should know.
最好的朋友，有些事应让你知道
Nay! There is nothing I should know.
不！我什么都不应知道
You are Beowulf.
Beowulf the mighty, the hero!
你是贝奥武甫，强大的贝奥武甫，英雄！
The slayer and destroyer of demons!
魔族的杀戮者，毁灭者
Now, let us kill this flying devil
where it sleeps
我们现在去那飞翔的恶魔的睡房
将他杀死
and get on with our bloody lives!
回来继续我们的生活！
-Do you want me to go in with you?
-No.
- 要我跟你进去吗？
- 不
Good.
好
Beowulf.
贝奥武甫
It has been a long time.
已经过了很久
Take your damned horn
and leave my land in peace.
把这可咒的黄金角拿去，给我的土地和平
Too late, my love.
太迟了，我的爱
Odin's swifan balls!
奥丁的命根啊！
It's heading for Herot!
它向西奥鹿特去了！
Now!
放！
Hrothgar.
洛斯戈
Come on, come on !
Come on ! Come on !
快，快！
快！快！
Damn you !
可咒的！
I'll have your lizard head on a spike!
我定要将你这蜥蜴脑袋钉上挂起！
No!
不！
My Lord !
陛下！
No!
不！
Over here! Attend the Queen.
这儿！保护王后
-Attend the Queen.
- 保护王后
I told you we were too old to be heroes.
我告诉过你，我们太老，已做不成英雄
Let's get you to a healer.
该你为找位医士
Not this time, old friend.
这次不要，老朋友
You are Beowulf.
你是贝奥武甫
A little thing like this
isn't going to finish you off.
这一点点小事不会让你死亡
Do you hear her?
你可曾听说过她？
I hear nothing.
我从未听说
Grendel's mother,
my son's mother, my. . .
哥伦德之母，我儿子的母亲
我的……
-No, my Lord.
-My. . .
- 不，陛下
- 我的……
You killed Grendel's mother
when we were young.
你杀死了哥伦德的母亲
当我们年轻的时候
They sing of it.
人们将此事传唱
Too late for lies, Wiglaf.
欺骗已经太迟了，维格拉夫
Too late.
太迟了
He was
他曾是
the bravest of us.
在我们当中最勇敢的
He was the prince
他是领袖
of all warriors.
胜过所有的战士
His name will live forever.
他的名字，将永远流传
His song shall be sung forever.
他的传说，将永远传颂下去